Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives 1982-2001 MSS 231
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXII: Pride and Progress / The Right Stuff
  - Subseries A: Cablecast Programs, 1985-1990
    - 1987
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 22 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/26/1987] (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0740)
        2. Discussion of the lawsuit against Governor Cuomo's "anti-sex guidelines"
        3. Discussion of gay activism against anti-gay politicians and finding allies in politics
        4. Balancing sex education and AIDS education for children and young adults
        5. Andy Humm on politicians advocating abstinence to counter AIDS
        6. News Watch, CDC adds dementia and emaciation to AIDS symptoms
        7. Holland, upscale condom boutique opens on outskirts of Amsterdam's red light district
        8. Smoking found to possibly cause impotence
        9. A Florida man goes on a shooting rampage because he believed that some people thought he was gay
        11. Lavender Health, Ron Vauchon with Ellen Zaltzberg discussing various conferences centered around gay health issues
        1. Show Bits with George Trahanis, interview with Bob Bowyer of the off-Broadway show, "Funny Feet"
        2. Olivia Negron interviews Karen Abbott and Bob Werner, two activists who placed pro-gay stickers around "Heritage USA," the park owned by Tammy Faye and Jim Bakker
        3. Interview with Joe di Sabito about condom companies avoiding advertising in gay media
        4. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with Mark Thompson, author and cultural editor of "The Advocate" magazine
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 23 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/29/1987] (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0741)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 24 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/5/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0742)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Joyce Hunter, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Updates regarding the National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights
        3. Discussion of a new biography of Leonard Bernstein that outs him and multiple others in his circle, and the status of closeted celebrities
        4. Ronald Reagan and George Bush booed after speaking in favor of mandatory AIDS testing, also necessity of having medical professionals discuss the issues, and not politicians
        5. Andy Humm on Mario Cuomo and Ed Koch "getting tough" on AIDS and the issue of mandatory testing
        6. Clips from President Reagan and Vice-President George Bush's speeches on mandatory testing, booing of audience, and clips from the June 1st 1987 protest in front of the White House
        7. News Watch, French researchers discover second, genetically different strain of HIV which also causes AIDS
        8. "The San Francisco Chronicle" apologizes for omitting the names of surviving homosexual partners in obituaries
        9. In a national poll, AIDS is found to be the third greatest fear of youths aged 8-17, behind only kidnapping and nuclear war, with 65% saying they are "very concerned" with AIDS, and other statistics
        10. Liberace's estate sues Riverside County, CA as the coroner's linking the star's death with AIDS damaged his posthumous reputation
        COMMERCIAL: Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center
        12. Lavender Health, interview with Rona Affoumado, clinic coordinator of the Community Health Project
        1. Naming Names, criticism of The New York Times, Sunday Magazine
        COMMERCIAL: Heritage of Pride, 24-hour Dance Marathon
        2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, interview with David Drake of "Vampire Lesbians of Sodom"
        3. Rebroadcast of Episode 6 of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Jock's Itch"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 25 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/12/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0743)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, and Maureen Brady, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Conversation with Congressman Ted Weiss, chief sponsor of the Federal Lesbian and Gay Rights Bill, and advocate for greater AIDS funding
        COMMERCIAL: Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center Fundraiser
        3. Continued conversation with Ted Weiss
        4. Andy Humm on Mayor Ed Koch's defense of Cardinal O'Connor and sponsorship of abstinence-only AIDS education
        5. News Watch, AIDS-positive man in Birmingham, Alabama spits in the face of a baby, which City Council attempts to classify this as "attempted murder," although a member of the Alabama State Health Department declares transmission by spitting "very unlikely"
        6. A federal lawsuit has been brought against Prudential Insurance Company by a business-owner who was tested for HIV antibodies without his knowledge or consent
        7. William Hoffman, the playwright of "As Is," criticizes PBS for refusing to air the movie-version of the play due to the possible reaction of Southern stations to the positive depiction of a gay relationship
        8. West Seneca, New York, board approves changing the name of "Gay Drive" to "Fawn Trail" due to resident's disapproval
        10. Lavender Health, interview with Michael Baker, interagency planner of the NYC Department of Health
        1. Naming Names, criticism of anti-gay extremist Paul Cameron
        COMMERCIAL: Interart Theatre
        2. Rebroadcast of Episode 7 [misidentified on tape by announcer] of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Poetry in Motion"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 26 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/22/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0744)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Jim Levin, Jean Elizabeth Glass, and Lou Maletta, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        3. Interview with Lou Maletta on the Stonewall Riots of June 28th, 1969
        4. Continuation of discussion about the effects of Stonewall on the current gay community and gay advocacy
        5. Andy Humm on Bishop Emerson Moore and his hypocrisy speaking against gay rights as a gay man
        6. News Watch, the Boston Lesbian and Gay Alliance is pushing for the city to hire gays as police due to a seven-fold increase in violence against homosexuals
        7. 6 year study in Sweden allows for the passage of a bill granting long-term homosexual couples the same rights as common law marriages
        8. Police wear bright yellow gloves to arrest pro-gay protesters in Washington DC, but South Carolinian police wear anti-AIDS suits against the perceived treat of contracting the virus
        9. The Beastie Boys made anti-gay comments in a music magazine, so their recording label, CBS Records, donated $2000 to the Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project
        11. Lavender Health, interview with Aaron Rudner, Deafness Project Director at the Institute for the Protection of Lesbian and Gay Youth
        1. Olivia Negron interviews Peggy Shaw and Lois Weaver, two founders of the lesbian performance troupe, "Split Britches"
        2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of cabaret show, "The Wallowitching Hour"
        3. Rebroadcast of Episode 8 of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Fit for a Queen"
        4. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, announcement of playwright Charles Ludlam's death, clips from a performance of his play, "The Ventriloquist's Wife"
        5. Olivia Negron announces important numbers to call, closing credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 27 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: unknown], [1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0745)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Jim Levin, and David Strah, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Discussion of Ed Koch's decision to honor anti-gay bishop, Francis Mugavero, despite Brooklyn College refusing to honor the bishop, including clips of Koch defending his decision
        3. Discussion of love lives in the age of AIDS, and changes to sexual behavior of the community
        4. Andy Humm on coming out
        5. News Watch, study by Johns Hopkins of 5000 homosexual men finds sexual activities and lifestyles changing, including increases in celibacy, condom usage, and monogamous relationships, also finds a decrease in sexual partners
        6. 12 remaining Los Angeles bathhouses required to follow new safe-sex guidelines that prohibit certain activities such as anal sex without a condom, and anonymous group sex, while sponsoring AIDS education
        7. Florida boy committed by a judge to a psychiatric ward because he was HIV positive and remained sexually active
        8. Homosexual man fired from the National Security Assosciation for being "psychologically unstable" wins the right to a trial
        9. Sports Report, clips from a spoof exercise video starring Ferdinand Marcos and other dictators
        10. Lavender Health, interview with Cook Friedman, director of the group Education in a Disabled Gay Environment
        1. Naming Names, criticism of Steven Weinstock, producer of WNET television program "Currents"
        2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Alan Bowne's play, "Beirut"
        COMMERCIAL: "Take a Ferry on the Fourth" event
        3. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with the stars of "Beirut," Michael David Morrison and Laura San Giacomo
        4. Rebroadcast of Episode 9 of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Hair Today, Gone Tomorrow"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 28 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/7/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0746)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 29 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/14/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0747)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Rev. Bernard Lynch and Eleanor Cooper, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Discussion about Catholicism and homosexuality.
        3.Discusson about the differences between the way gay and straight communities responded to the AIDS crisis.
        4.News Watch, President Regan nominates Circuit Court of Appeals judge Robert H. Bork to the Supreme Court
        5.Personal advertisment placed by Ft. Worth police department seen as a attack on homosexuality by ACLU and Gay Alliance
        6.Committee of Outraged Lesbians (COOL) formed to combat racist or discriminatory practices in dance clubs urges the boycotting of events sponsored by Shescape Productions
        7. New ruiling by FDA makes Investigational New Drugs (IND) available to people suffering from serious diseases, GCN contacts FDA to see how this affects people with AIDS
        8.Lavender Health, Ellen Zaltzberg interviews Joe Stanton from Senior Action in Gay Enviornment (SAGE) about the services and history of the organization
        9.Closing credits
        1. Naming Names, criticism of Natt Hemtoff's article which lambasts health professionals for not supporting mandatory testing for AIDS
        2.GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Hair Today, Gone Tomorrow Pt. 2"
        COMMERCIAL: Manscape
        5."Suds": "East Meets West Side"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 30 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/17/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0748)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Jewelle Gomez, and Darryl Yates-Rist, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Discussion about mandatory AIDS testing for everyone and coming out
        3. Discussion with Darryl Yates-Rist about his travels across the USA and his experiences with various gay communities.
        4.Introduction of the group ACT-UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power)
        5.News watch, John Paul II's visit to San Francisco prompts antviolence statement between gay community leaders and the Roman Catholic Diocese of San Francisco
        2. John [Wahlia] of Zambia, Africa is at a controversy for not sleeping with widowed sister-in-law whose husband died of AIDS
        3. Rev. Rose Mary Denman, Methodist minister and lesbian takes a leave of abscense in a effort to change Methodist position on being a practicing gay minister
        COMMERCIAL: L'image
        5.GCN Sports, Dr. Tom Waddell, founder of Gay Games, died from complications due to AIDS, rundown of sports results, "Spy Magazine" report about an 18'' rubber penis in locker room, and clip of 16 year old gymnist Trent Davis
        COMMERCIAL: First Hand
        6. Lavender Health, Interview with David Worthheimer, Execuitve Director of Lesbian and Gay Anti-Violence Project, talks about organization.
        7.Closing credits
        1. Naming Names, criticism of Regan nominee, US Circuit Court Judge Robert Bork to Supreme Court
        COMMERCIAL:L'image
        COMMERCIAL:Manscape
        2.GCN soap opera "SUDS" episode, "Playmates"
        COMMERCIAL:The Monster
        COMMERCIAL:L'Image3.GCN soap opera, "SUDS" episode, "Playmates"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 31 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/24/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0749)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 32 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/12/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0750)
        1. Naming Names, criticism of Regan's AIDS panel
        2.GCN soap opera "SUDS" episode, "Chapter 13"
        COMMERCIAL:L'Image
        3.GCN soap opera, "SUDS" episode, "Chapter 13"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 33 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/19/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0751)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Jim Levin and Philip Reed, member of the Minority Task Force, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Discussion about minorities with AIDS with footage of a protest outside of St. Patrick's Cathedral
        COMMERCIAL: Prevention campaign by SWISS-AIDS-ASSISTANCE
        3.Continuation of discussion on minorities with AIDS
        4.James Minter, member of the Front Runners, talks about engaging political canidates on AIDS topics
        5. News Watch, Man gets custody of his partners son after he dies of AIDS
        6.Public pool closed after an HIV positive man swam in it in Williamson, West Virginia
        7.GCN Sports, Professional football teams offer voluntary AIDS testing for players, Tom Cousineau denies that he's gay, footage of diver Matt Scoggin and Greg Louganis
        8.Lavender Health interview with Michael Shernoff, from Chelsea Psychotherapy Associates, talks about finding a therapist
        1. Show Bitz, discussion about the play, Steel Magnolias
        2.Naming Names, criticism about the AIDS reporting of newspaper,"The Daily News"
        COMMERCIAL: "Stop AIDS" The Swiss Federal Office of Public Health
        3.Media Watch, Interview with pornographer and musican Chris Rage, features music video with footage of Rage's films
        4.Inside Out, comedy sketch/satire where Sisky and Ebie look at homoeroticism in the film "The Color of Money" and "Top Gun"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 34 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/26/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0752)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Jim Levin and Mel Rosin, Director of the NY State AIDS Institute, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Discussion about how democrats Ed Koch and Governor Cuomo have dealt with the AIDS crisis.
        3.Footage of "New York Post" AIDS Forum, August 6 at the Sheraton Hotel and discussion of New York City Mayor, Ed Koch's speech at the forum
        4. NYC Council Members and opponents of gay rights, Aileen Ryan and Thomas Cuite died, Gay rights activist Tom Doerr died
        5.Lavender Health, Interview with Dr. Harold Kooden of the Lesbian and Gay Mental Health Advisory Group
        6.Closing credits
        1.Naming Names, criticism of Senator Gordon Humphrey of New Hampshire who criticized Regan's appointment of Dr. Frank Lilly to his AIDS panel
        2.Media Watch, Interviews with Dan Sauso, Lisa Heft and Ron from The Names Project
        COMMERCIAL: The Islanders Club
        3.Show Bitz, discussion about Charles Bush's play, Psycho Beach Party
        4.Inside Out, discussion about "lightness" in commercial products.
        5. Introduction of Lyle's Deck, a gay resort on South Padre Island, Texas
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 35 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/31/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0753)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Jim Levin and guest Dr. Frank Lilly, only opendly gay member of the presidential commission on AIDS, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Dr. Frank Lilly goes into detail about the reasons for his selection and the commissions mandate among other things.
        COMMERCIAL: San Francisco AIDS Foundation
        3.Continuation of interview with Dr. Frank Lily
        4. Dr. Burton Lee meets with AIDS activists
        5.News Watch,Stirling Colgate has developed a software that projects levels of AIDS infection
        6.Meridian, Mississipi citizens protest the existence of a local gay bar called Poppers
        7. University of California doctor is testing a drug to help with impotency.
        8.Article on lesbianism in magazine called, "New Woman"
        9. Announcement regarding the October 11th March on Washington
        COMMERCIAL:First Hand
        10.GCN Sports interviews bowler Gutter George from [VBL]
        11. Lavender Health, Interview with Ellen Zaltzberg, an Education Coordinator of the Office of Gay and Lesbian Health Concerns of the NYC Department of Health, talks about homophobia
        12.Closing credits
        1.Show Bitz, interview with Charles Bush
        2.Naming Names, "Money Magazine" recieves criticism after publishing an article about a gay couple's finances
        COMMERCIAL:The Islanders Club
        3.Just Ask Raz,Announcement about play, "Love Goddess" among other things
        4.Inside Out, Introducing Paco Rabanne
        5.Media Watch, Interview with Arthur Kirson, Cabaret Performer
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 36 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/8/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0754)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 37 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/15/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0755)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Jim Levin, Joyce Hunter, Eleanor Cooper, and guest Tom Duane, Chelsa Democratic District Leader, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Footage and rememberance of civil rights and gay activist, Bayard Rustin
        3.Discussion and criticism of the Regan AIDS Commission
        4.Discussion about an incident in Florida where a house was burned because three HIV positive children lived there
        COMMERCIAL:San Francisco AIDS Foundation
        5. Discussion about housing rights for surviving partners of AIDS victims
        6.Further discussion about Bayard Rustin
        7.Discussion about the October 11th March on Washington
        8.News Watch, Soviet Union tests people suspected of having HIV
        9.Rosemary Denman, Methodist minister, was suspended by ministry for being openly gay
        10.STD Clinic in Seattle Washington makes a greeting card/gift certificate for an AIDS Test
        11.NY Gay Community Center sponsors its first orientation
        12.GCN Sports, Footage of gymnasts Scott Johnson, Tim Daggett, and Casimiro Suarez
        13.Lavender Health, Interview with Richard Heyl from Orientation NYC
        14.Closing credits
        1.Show Bitz, Review of the cabaret show, Phillip Officer
        COMMERCIAL:Gay Treasures
        2.Naming Names, criticism of "Associated Press" obituary for Bayard Rustin for the omission of his gay civil rights work
        3.John Dietrich, from The Islanders Club, talks about the upcoming cruise
        4.Media Watch, Interview with Leonard J. Martelli and Bill Messina, authors of "When Someone You Know Has AIDS"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 38 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/23/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0756)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Jim Levin, David Strah, and Eleanor Cooper, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Discussion about legislature for censoring homophobic remarks by representatives
        3.Discussion about Pope John Paul II
        4.Discussion about Supreme Court nomination of Robert Bork
        5.Criticism of Regan's AIDS Panel
        6.Washington Countdown, Discussion about events and promotion surrounding the October 11, March on Washington
        7.Interview with congressman Tedd Weiss and Bill Green about the Lesbian and Gay rights bill concerning public employment
        8.Discussion about ads for the October 11, March on Washington
        9.News Watch, AIDS Fraud and phony treatments
        10.Group study about the coping mechanisms of men who took a HIV Antibody Test
        11.Censoring of homophic remarks by political representatives
        COMMERCIAL:DIA Art Foundation-Art Against AIDS
        Lavender Health, interview with Tony Davis of VILAGE (Visually Impared in a Lesbian and Gay Enviornment)
        12.Closing Credits
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 39 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/23/1987] (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0757)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm and special guests Denise Alexander, Ortez Alderson, Phillip Reed and Dr. Marjorie Hill, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Discussion about race relations in the gay and lesbian political movement
        COMMERCIAL:National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights
        3.Discussion about the issues of black gay and lesbians
        4.Criticism about the Pope and his views on homosexuality and AIDS
        5.Washington Countdown, discussion about political candidates who have supported the march
        6.Announcement about The Names Project
        7.Guests Tom Stoddard (Lambda Legal Defense) and Tim Sweeney (Gay Men's Health Crisis) discuss anti-discriminatory policies in regards to AIDS
        8.News Watch, Chicago doctor has been restored to his duties
        9.ACLU called upon Regan to reconsider his Advisory AIDS Commission
        10.Dr. Robert Gallo, co-discoverer of the AIDS virus, has blasted pharmacetual companies for not taking a bigger inititative in research development
        11.Amsterdam developed a monument for Lesbians and Gays
        12.Lavender Heatlh, interview with Shelly Neiderbach, founder of the Crime Victims Counseling Services Unit
        13.Closing Credits
        1.Media Watch, Interview with Eric Perez of the Third World People of Color Caucas
        2.Perry Brass, "Short Bits of Wisdom From Daddy"
        3.Just Ask Raz
        COMMERCIAL: Gay Treasures
        4.Jeanne Leonard talks about her tribute to Judy Garland
        5.Interview with Jim Hubbard from the NY Lesbian & Gay Experimental Film Festival
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 40 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/30/1987] (Box 49, Media ID: 231.0758)
        1. Gay Week in Review, with Jim Levin, David Strah, and Christopher Lynn, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2.Discussion about how AIDS affects the classroom and the court room
        3. Discussion about convicting a man dying of AIDS who robbed a woman
        COMMERCIAL:Human Rights Campaign
        4.NYC Council nominates Joseph Lisa for Health Committee Chair
        5.Washington Countdown, discussion about political candidates and celebrities who are supporting the March on Washington
        6. Interview with Susan Cavin and David Harris who talk about Non Violent Civil Disobedience
        7.Fundraiser for the March on Washington at The Tunnel
        8.News Watch, Initial trials of the drug DDC have been stopped because its too toxic
        Brendan O'Rourke, an AIDS patient, recieved a hug from Pope John Paul II